Guide to the Sigma Delta Epsilon records, 1920-2012
Sigma Delta Epsilon records, 1920-2012
- Series VI. Copies of Publications, Bulletins and Newsletters
  - Name Changed to Sigma Delta Epsilon Graduate Women in Science BULLETIN
    - Vol. 63, No. 2 Winter 2001 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 63, No. 3 Spring 2001 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 63, No. 4 Spring 2002 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 64, No. 1 Fall 2002 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 64, No. 2 Winter 2003 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 65, No. 1 Fall 2003 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 65, No. 2 Winter 2004 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 65, No. 3 Spring 2004 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 66, No. 1 Fall 2004 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 66, No. 2 Winter 2005 (Box 8)
    - Winter 2005 (Box 8)
    - Spring 2006 (Box 8)
    - Winter 2007 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 69, No. 1 Fall 2007 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 69, No. 2 Spring 2008 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 70, No. 1 Fall 2008 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 70, No. 2 Winter 2008-2009 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 70, No. 3 Summer 2009 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 71, No. 1 Fall 2009 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 71, No. 2 Winter 2009-2010 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 71, No. 3 Spring/Summer 2010 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 72, No. 1 Fall 2010 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 72, No. 2 Winter 2010-2011 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 72, No. 3 Spring/Summer 2011 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 73, No. 1 Fall 2011 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 73, No. 2 Winter 2011-2012 (Box 8)
    - Vol. 73, No. 3 Spring/Summer 2012 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters
    From the summer of 1969 (Vol. 1) through 1979 (Vol. IX) Newsletters were published in addition to Bulletins. Purpose of Newsletters as to fill a communication gap between spring and fall publications. However, this schedule was changed during those years.
    When Helen Haller became Editor, she incorporated the numbering system into the Bulletin numberings.
    - Vol. I: No.1 1969 (Box 8)
    - Vol. II: No.1 1970 (Box 8)
    - Vol. II: No. 2 (October) 1970 (Box 8)
    - Vol. II: No.3 April1971 (Box 8)
    - Vol. III: No.2 (No.1 missing) (October) 1971 (Box 8)
    - Vol. IV: No.1 (February) 1972 (Box 8)
    - Vol. IV: No.2 (September) 1972 (Box 8)
    - Vol. V: No.1 (March) 1973 (Box 8)
    - Vol. V: No.2 (September) 1973 (Box 8)
    - Vol. VI: No.1 (January) 1974 (Box 8)
    - Vol. VII: No.1 (September) 1975 (Box 8)
    - Vol. VIII: No.2 (February) 1976 (Box 8)
    - Vol. VIII: No.2 (February) 1977 (Box 8)
    - Vol. IX: No.1 (Spring) 1979 (Box 8)
    - Vol. IX: No.2 (Summer) 1979 (Box 8)
- Series VII. Chapter Meetings
  - Kits from Grand Chapter Meetings 1970-1986
    - June, 1970 Madison, Wisconsin (Box 9)
    - June, 1971 Ithaca, New York; December - Philadelphia (Box 9)
    - June, 1972 Columbus, Ohio December - Washington (Box 9)
    - June, 1973 Lincoln, Nebraska (Box 9)
    - June, 1974 Leavenworth, Kansas; February - San Francisco (Box 9)
    - June, 1975 College Park, Maryland; January - New York City (Box 9)
    - June, 1976 Champaign, Illinois; February - Boston (Box 9)
    - June, 1977 Madison, Wisconsin; February - Denver (Box 9)
    - June, 1978 San Diego, California (Box 9)
    - June, 1979 Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 9)
    - June, 1980 Arlington, Virginia; January - San Francisco (Minutes only) (Box 9)
    - June, 1981 Ithaca, New York; January - Toronto (Minutes only) (Box 9)
    - June, 1982 St. Paul, Minneapolis; January - Washington (Minutes only) (Box 9)
    - May, 1983 Detroit, Michigan (Box 9)
    - May, 1984 New York, New York (Placed in archives January 18, 1985) (Box 9)
    - May, 1985 Los Angeles, California (Included in archives 'current' 1987) (Box 9)
    - May, 1986 Madison, Wisconsin (Included in archives 'current' 1987) (Box 9)
  - Grand Chapter Meeting reports prior to 1970
    These are not in separate kits by years. The reports are usually brief and have been filed in groups in folders
    - 1948 Reports from officers and committees-- apparently no meeting held. (Box 12)
    - 1949 No National Convention--conducted by mail (Box 12)
    - 1950 New York City (Box 12)
    - 1951 Philadelphia (Box 12)
    - 1952 Ithaca, New York (Box 12)
    - 1953 Madison, Wisconsin (Box 12)
    - 1954 Gainesville, Florida (Box 12)
    - 1955 Minneapolis (Box 12)
    - 1956 New York City (Box 12)
    - 1957 Indianapolis (Box 12)
    - 1958 Washington (Box 12)
    - 1959 Missing (Box 12)
    - 1960 New York City (December) (Box 12)
    - 1961 Purdue University (August) (Box 12)
    - 1962 Missing (Box 12)
    - 1963 Cleveland (December) (Box 12)
    - 1964 Montreal (December) (Box 12)
    - 1965 Berkeley (December) (Box 12)
    - 1966 Washington, D.C. (December) (Box 12)
    - 1967 Missing (Box 12)
    - 1968 Dallas (December) (Box 12)
    - 1969 Boston (December) (Box 12)
- Series VIII. Items Added October 1, 1987
  The following items were deposited in the Cornell University Library Archives by the National Organization of Sigma Delta Epsilon, Graduate Women in Science.
  - Minutes of National Council Meeting and Grand Chapter Meeting
    May 24-25 1986 International House Philadelphia, Penn. Contents are Typed Copies and Tapes
    - Grand Chapter Meeting (3 Tapes) (Box 10)
    - National Council Meeting (2 Tapes) (Box 10)
    - 65th Anniversary Speeches (2 Tapes) (Box 10)
  - Other
    - Interim National Council Meeting: February, 16, 1987 Hyatt Regency Hotel Chicago, Ill.
    - 1986 Project Reports From Grant-in-aid Recipients: Gail Foreman, Marilyn Lloyd (Box 10)
    - 1986 Publication, Brief Report, Final Report: Fellowship Winner, Pamela J. Stewart (Box 10)
    - 1986 Eloise Gerry Winners and Honorary Mention: Application and Recommendations (Box 10)
    - National Honorary Awards 1987: Applications and Recommendations (Box 10)
    - National Honorary Awards 1987: Recommendations, Vitae, Publications (Box 10)
      Dr. Rita Colwell, Dr. Barbara McClintock, Dr. Theressa Campbell Stadtman
    - Kit From Grand Chapter Meeting: June 24-28, 1987 Macalester College St. Paul Minnesota (Box 10)
    - Margaret Pittman, Article by Gail McBride "Down to a 40-hour work-week." from Bulletin of Medical Alumni Assoc., Medicine on the Midway, University of Chicago Spring 1987. (Award from SDE Jan. 1986 to Margaret Pittman, See page 8 of article) (Box 10)
    - Comstock Hall: Dedication Cornell University May 1986 (Box 10)
    - Vi and Mam: The lives of Viola Louise Sommermeyer and Carrie Murray by Karl H. Sommermeyer (Box 10)
- Series IX. Items Added November 21, 1992
  - Honorary Members
    - 1990 Pov, Schraer, Cunningham (Box 11)
    - 1989 Horde, Simmons (Box 11)
    - 1989 Hopper, Huang, Thompson, Ride (Box 11)
    - 1988 Good, Cobb, Berdanier, Iglewski (Box 11)
    - 1988 Colwell, McClintock, Stadtman (Box 11)
    - 1988 Robbins, Hollinshead, Weisburger (Box 11)
    - 1988 Brooks-Wallace, Breuchley, Mondy (Box 11)
    - 1988 Caserio, McCoy, Greisheimer (Box 11)
    - 1988 Carlson, Miller, Harvley (Box 11)
    - 1979 Pike, Quiggle (Box 11)
    - 1965 Rogick, Dyer, Maver, Whiting, Hafkesbring (Box 11)
    - Various: Wyckoff, Pittman, Horde, Diller, Mead, Bunting, Cooper, Chase, Wind, Quimby, Webster, Geray, Lonsdale, Kittnell, young, Reid, McWhinnie, Horstmann, Chu, Metz, Piccard, Apgar, Laucefield, Reynolds, Whiting (Box 11)
    - National membership directories, 1986, 1998, 1990, 1994, 1997, 2000 (Box 11)
    - 87th Year History, by Michelle D. Leibrand Wahlin, edited by Sister Patricia Shaffer and Gloria Gridley, 1921-2008 (Box 11)
    - Grand Chapter Meeting Kits, 2009-2012 (Box 11)
- Series X. Items Added
  - Snapshots of Catherine Foley Quigley, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Snapshots at Grand Chapter Meeting, June 1982 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Photos Used In History by Ruth Dickie, 1979-1986 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Snapshots of Grand Chapter Meeting, Chattanooga, June 1988 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Snapshots of Grand Chapter Meeting, San Diego, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Snapshots of Grand Chapter Meeting, Washington DC, June 1991 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Installation of Officers,St. Paul, MN, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Snapshots, June 2000 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Snapshots of Grand Chapter Meeting, Madison, WI, June 2000 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Initiation and Other Materials Received From Helen Stewart, Maquoketa, IA, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence about Eltora Schroeder (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Documentation of FASEB Services rendered, 1980-1983 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence of Marie Conklin(President), 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence about Ethaline Cortelyou (Secretary), 1983-1986 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence of Ruth Dickie, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Drafts and Materials for History by Ruth Dickie, 1979-1986 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence of Ariel Hollinshead (President), 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence of Maxine Heinitz,(President), 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence of Monique Braude,(President), 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence of Katherine Baum,(President), 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Proclamation of Women in Science Weekend, Davis, CA, March 1994 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Leadership Development for Women in Science, March 1994 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence of H.D.Haller,(President), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Meeting attendees, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Meeting Preparation and Correspondence, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Copy of Will of Ruth Dickie, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - American Women In Science Before The Civil War Publication By Elizabeth Wagner, 1992 (Box 12)
  - Cartoon Humor Book For Working Women, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Book For Working Women, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Making Success Your Reality, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Time of Transition: Women in Science, 1979-1986 (Box 12)
  - Graduate Women in Science History, 1986-1996 (Box 12)
  - Science Is For Girls, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Writing About Science (Box 12)
  - Graduate Women in Science, Policies and Procedures Manual, June 2000 (Box 12)
  - Records About Theta Chapter, 1971-1989 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Theta Chapter Financial Records, Columbus,Ohio (Box 12)
  - Officer Installation Ceremony (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Addresses And Information (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Membership Directory, Theta Chapter, Columbus,Ohio (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Framed Certificate Establishing Chapter at Iowa State College, 1925 (Box 14)
  - Two Framed Certificates Relating to Women in Science Week in Massachusetts, 2004 (Box 15)
- Series XI. Cassette Tapes
  - Today's Women in Science, By Lamda Chapter (Los Angeles) (Box 12)
  - Grand Chapter Meetings and National Council Meetings, 1987-1991 (Box 13)